ANA SILVA

SOFTWARE ENGINEER

PERSONAL PROFILE

I was a biochemist for 15 years, when I decided to follow my passion for coding and study Software Engineering Immersive.I always enjoy solving puzzles, learning and building things. I used to be challenged every day as a scientist and I am ready to apply my problem solving skills, analytical and logical thinking in my future profession in tech.

SKILLS

- JavaScript, HTML, CSS, Vanilla JS, jQuery, Underscore, Ruby,
REACT.js, JSX, Vue.js, Ruby on Rails, Node.js
- SQLite, Postgresql, use of external APIs, Ajax and Axios
- GitHub, Heroku and Firebase deployment
- Image manipulation using Adobe Photoshop,
Adobe Illustrator, ImageJ.
Some experience:

- Test Driven Development, Bootstrap, Meteor, MongoDB, Perl

ACHIEVEMENTS

- PhD scholarship awarded by Science and Technology Foundation, Portugal, 2004-2008 - Merit Award for Top 10 Year 1 Undergraduate, Science Faculty of University of Lisbon, 1999/2000

CONTACT DETAILS

Phone: 0499 143 374
Email: apgsilva81@gmail.com
LinkedIn: linkedin.com/in/ana-pg-silva/
Github: github.com/anapgsilva

RELATED PROJECTS

Memory Card Game: anapgsilva.github.io/memory_game/memory_game/

This is a simple card game where the player needs to turn two cards that match. Built using Javascript, HTML and CSS.

Tic-Tac-Toe Game: anapgsilva.github.io/tictactoe-nxn/

This is a classical game of noughts and crosses, with the option of either a 3X3 or a 9X9 board game. Built using Javascript, HTML and CSS.

Movie Library: github.com/anapgsilva/movie_library

Users can create their own libraries and populate them with movies, which information is pulled directly from the Internet Movie DataBase. Based on their libraries, users can request a movie suggestion. Project built solely in Ruby on Rails.

Restaurant website: github.com/anapgsilva/restaurant_client

Users can create their own account and make orders for pick-up or delivery. Website built using REACT and RAILS.

Colouring Application: colourfill.firebaseapp.com/

User chooses black and white pictures from an API or takes a photo from camera. Website built using React and was hosted on Firebase (real-time database and function).

EXPERIENCE

INSTRUCTIONAL ASSISTANT SEI-35

General Assembly Sydney, since Jan 2020

POSTDOCTORAL RESEARCH FELLOW

University of Sydney, Australia, 2012-2019

Studies of the Nucleosome Remodeling and Deacetylase complex. During this time, I wrote a few scripts in Perl for data analysis. I demoed, supervised and trained Science students; examined Master thesis; and spoke at conferences. University of Manchester, UK, 2009-2011

Structural-based drug design project to develop new drugs against *Mycobacterium Tuberculosis* protein phosphatases. I supervised and trained both undergraduate and PhD students.

University of York, UK, 2009

Determined the 3D-structure of a few kinase-drug complexes from the Malaria-causing ${\it Plasmodium\ Falciparum}$.

EDUCATION

GENERAL ASSEMBLY SYDNEY, AUSTRALIA
Software Engineering Immersive SEI-34, Oct-Dec 2019

UNIVERSITY OF YORK, UK PhD in Chemistry, 2004-2009

UNIVERSITY OF LISBON, PORTUGAL

Bachelor in Chemistry, 1999-2003